Victor Évrard FOTSO FOTSO

C# Developer for Pre-Trade Calibration & Pricing Systems - Fixed Income

Curious and passionate about IT, with a particular interest in finance, I have solid Front Office experience in Fixed Income and in real-time calibration and pricing applications development.

Work Experience

Front Office Pre Trade Commando C# — Société Générale La Défense

Since February 2022

- Developed and maintained pre-trade tools for Fixed Income Front Office desks (Rates, Cash & Inflation) in a fast-paced trading environment.
- Delivered tactical and strategic enhancements using C# to support curve calibration, product pricing (Swaps, Bonds, FX & XCCY), and indicator computations.
- Contributed to the industrialization of legacy Excel-based pricers into robust and maintainable applications.

C#, .NET, Excel, VBA, Fixed Income, Pre-trade

Data Analyst — BNP PARIBAS Paris 09 Opéra, France

From March 2021 to August 2021

Identified and analyzed Group-level risk trends; contributed to the development of a centralized risk data aggregator. Optimized and automated recurring reporting processes to improve efficiency and data reliability.

Python, Pandas, Numpy, Excel, VBA, SharePoint

Commando Front (then Middle) Office — Société Générale La Défense, Paris

From October 2019 to October 2020

Contributed to the migration of legacy Excel/VBA tools into Python-based web applications for operational risk reduction and improved maintainability.

Python, Flask, FastAPI, Django, Pandas, Bootstrap, Socket.io

Education

Specialized Master's in Data Science for Finance — NEOMA BS Paris

From December 2020 to 2021

Data Science, Quantitative Finance, Stochastic Modelling and Derivatives Pricing, Optimization Techniques, Econometrics, Risk Management, Numerical Methods in C++, Market Microstructure

Master's-level Engineering Degree with a major in Finance — ESIGELEC Rouen

From 2017 to 2020

Software Engineering, Quantitative Finance, Applied Machine Learning

Projects

Professional Thesis: A machine learning approach on European call options pricing — NEOMA BS Paris

From March 2021 to November 2021

Built supervised learning models (Random Forest, XGBoost, SVR & Neural Networks) to estimate option premiums; benchmarked against Black-Scholes and assessed performance using cross-validation on both synthetic and historical data.

$\textbf{Vanilla Products and Options Pricing} \\ -- \\ \text{NEOMA BS Paris}$

From June 2021 to July 2021

Academic project focused on building a pricing engine for bonds, forwards, and European options using both analytical and simulation methods. Implemented models in C++ including Bachelier, Black-Scholes and Euler-based Monte Carlo simulations.

Al-based Detection of Aggressive Behavior in Urban Settings — ESIGELEC Rouen

From October 2019 to January 2020

DeepLearning, Computer Vision, PyTorch, OpenCV, Flask-Socket.io

vfotsofotso@gmail.com

% vefts.com

06 17 79 39 15

Other Projects

- Sentiment analysis for BTC and ETH price prediction Forecasting & Scoring, Deep Learning, Time Series, Data Visualization, Probabilities, WebSrapping, GDPR
- Volatility Surface
 Construction and Analysis
 Financial Modelling,
 Derivatives, Python, Data
 Science, Equities,
 Commodities
- Fraud Detection in Banking Transactions (Imbalanced Dataset)
 Statistics, Optimization, Predictive Analytics, Data resampling
- Portfolio Management
 Project
 CAL, Efficient Frontier,
 Derivatives, Options and strategies

Other languages and tools

C#, Python, C++, C, R, Stata Pandas, NumPy, Matplotlib Next.js, Angular, Laravel, Node.js, Firebase, NoSql Flutter, Docker, Git

Languages

French

Mother tongue

English

Working Proficiency Plus - B2 (840 TOEIC score)

Chinese

Beginner Level

Hobbies

Music

Choir singing, Guitar, Piano

Others

Chess, Basketball

in victor-fotso